James C. Pelletier

35 Meadow Lane, Greenfield, MA, 01301 Tel: 434-509-2298 Email: jimcpelletier@hotmail.com

Background:

High energy senior level executive with over thirty years experience in the manufacturing of consumer and automotive products. A consistent top performer in strategic planning and execution, with a track record of success in organizations with revenues from \$100 million to \$700 million and employees ranging from 300 to 4,000. Other experiences include labor union contract negotiations with the United Auto Workers, acquisition and disposal of product lines and facilities, ISO 9000 & 14001, CNC Machining, lean manufacturing and 6S experience.

Experience:

- Catalyst in high velocity cultural changes in all business areas & provides organization with a living example. Results achieved were \$6 million in factory labor savings and \$8 million in material cost savings. Working capital reduced by \$30 million
- Customer focus modified organization and business processes that achieved 100% customer satisfaction in quality and deliveries. Numerous customer awards from major retailers including Wal*Mart and Sears as their number one supplier in applicable category
- Lead company negotiator in labor negotiations with UAW resulting in improvements in productivity and improved labor-management relations
- Reversed downward trend of sales in a seasonal business with new products. Increase in sales of \$80 million within two years
- Decision maker closed two major manufacturing facilities and consolidated into third resulting in \$15 million annual overhead savings

Deerfield Packaging, Turners Falls, MA.

Manager of Manufacturing, July 2011 to March 2012

- Consolidate 2 manufacturing facilities into a single new facility
- Oversee day to day manufacturing operations
- Improved on time deliveries by 80%

David Round, Streetsboro, Ohio

C.O.O., September 2007 to July 2011

- Engineered successful turnaround of all facets of new acquisition
- Oversaw optimization and implementation of new manufacturing software (ProfitKey)
- Implemented cultural changes and work cells
- Achieved 100% on time deliveries

C & J Associates, Forest Virginia

President & Owner, October 2005 to September 2007

- Provided consulting and assisted in staffing during an owner transition at Costa Precision
- Recent assignments included an aero space machining company in Claremont, NH for a turn around with customers such as Barnes, General Electric, Lockheed, and Northrop Grumman.

Tomkins Corporation: Schrader-Bridgeport, Altavista Virginia

Group Vice President, July 2004 to October 2005

- Supervised operations in five countries including China, India, Brazil and France with total sales of \$200 million and 1200 employees. Automotive tier one and two parts supplier coupled with aftermarket product line for retail
- Establish three manufacturing joint venture operations in China
- Increased working capital and cash flow by \$6,000,000 and \$4,000,000 respectively through supplier management, consolidation and consignment programs

Tomkins Corporation: Mayfran International, Cleveland, Ohio

President, February 2004 to July 2004

- Managed automotive and commercial conveying system product lines in Europe and the U.S.
- Increased company value in 6 months by 1% multiple of EBITDA through various improvements and the mitigation of numerous outstanding liabilities

Tomkins Corporation: Murray, Inc. Brentwood, Tennessee

President & COO, April 1996 to Sept. 2003

- Oversaw operations and sales of Murray's U.S., European and Asian Divisions with \$700 million in revenues and approximately 3,000 employees. Customers included Sears, Wal*Mart & Home Depot
- Generated \$18 million/year in cost reduction through transfer of \$100 million in products to China
- Transformed 3 million square foot facility into a lean concept plant resulting in \$25 million reduction in inventory
- Award recipient of prestigious "Best Mfg. Plant in State" (TN) and two "Excellence Awards in Environmental Improvements". 1999 & 2002
- Promoted six times in seven years

Tomkins Corporation: Smith & Wesson, Springfield, Massachusetts

Director, Advanced Product and Process Engineering, 1991 to 1996

- Transformed products and processes into a world class manufacturing facility within two years
- Tripled capital investment of \$15 million resulting in \$120 million in sales and profits of \$36 million

Kidder Stacy, Agawam, Massachusetts

Manager of Manufacturing Services, November 1986 to 1991

- Direct responsibility for Purchasing, Production Processes, Scheduling, and Quality in the manufacture of Large Printing Presses
- Introduced and implemented new manufacturing software to company, Profit-Key

Columbia Bicycle, Westfield, Massachusetts

Manager of Engineering, 1983 to 1986

Direct responsibility for Production Processes and Product for bicycles

Jarvis & Jarvis, Palmer Massachusetts

Assistant Manager of Engineering, 1979 to 1983

Responsible for Manufacturing Processes, Stamping and all Assembly

Education:

Central New England College of Technology Worcester Junior College Worcester Industrial Technical Institute Worcester Polytechnic Institute Bachelor of Engineering Technology, Cum Laude Associate Degree, Machine & Tool Design Technology Certificate, Design Drafting MBA Studies (approximately half complete)

Associations & Interests:

Senior Executive Network
Past Adjunct Professor, Springfield Technical Community College
Tennessee Association of Business - Board of Governors
JPTA Board Member (Job Placement Training Association)
21st Century Council
Restoration of homes
Society of Manufacturing Engineering